Guide to the Howard Dunham Barlow Collection, 1911-2000 (Bulk 1920-1958), MS001 MS 001
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Howard Dunham Barlow Collection
1911-2000, (Bulk 1920-1958)
1920-1958
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Barlow, Howard, 1892-1972.
MS 001
25 Linear Feet (22 boxes)
Howard Dunham Barlow was a radio pioneer, musician, composer, arranger and conductor. The Howard Dunham Barlow Collection consists of correspondence, newspaper and magazine clippings, recordings, original compositions, published choral arrangements, CBS program logs, scrapbooks, oral history, orchestral arrangements and works, prospective scripts, reviews of concerts, phonograph records, photographs, and writings.
17 inear feet
Provenance
In 1988, Nan Rogers, then Bethel Library Director, brought the material in this collection to the attention of James Pegolotti, then a library intern. She suggested the value of having the material in Western Connecticut State University Library for its research potential. Dr. Pegolotti arranged for this deposition and the Bethel Library Board approved the transfer in a letter from the Library Director dated January 30, 1989.
In 2018, Rob Feinson of Danbury donated a group of materials (mostly additional sheet music) purchased in the 1970s at a library book sale (either Danbury Public Library or Bethel Public Library).
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
Howard Dunham Barlow was a radio pioneer. He served as the conductor of serious music for the Columbia Broadcasting System from the first CBS broadcast on Sunday, September 18, 1927, through 1943, then moved to NBC as the conductor for the long running Voice of Firestone. He took this latter program from radio into television and was its conductor for fifteen years until 1958. For several years afterwards, Barlow conducted some "pops" concerts and became interested in the development of youth orchestras. By 1965, he was no longer conducting.
In 1965, HDB and his wife moved from Pound Ridge, New York, to Bethel, Connecticut. He began to write material to help young conductors understand the basis of being an effective conductor and wrote detailed essays on conducting specific works, and wrote "notes" on famous musicians and music events. With these, he hoped to interest radio stations in purchasing a series of five-minute stories he recorded for breaks through the broadcast day.
Mr. Barlow utilized the Bethel Public Library extensively during his years in the town. When he died in 1972, his widow Jeanette gave the library many boxes of memorabilia.
Sources:
note by: James Pegolotti, WCSU Librarian, February 1999
Scope and Content Note
The Howard Dunham Barlow Collection consists of correspondence, newspaper and magazine clippings, recordings, original compositions, published choral arrangements, CBS program logs, scrapbooks, oral history, orchestral arrangements and works, prospective scripts, reviews of concerts, phonograph records, photographs, and writings.
The materials are organized into 13 series, each one arranged chronologically. 1. Activities. 2. Columbia Broadcasting System. 3. Compositions by HDB. Series 4: HDB Guest Conducted Orchestra Concerts (reviews). 5. Oral History. 6. Orchestral Arrangements by HDB. 7. Photographs.
8. Prospective Scripts. 9. Scrapbooks. 10. Writings. 11. Phonograph Records (78 rpm disks).
12. Miscellany. 13. Research Materials.
The bulk of this collection dates from Howard Barlow's years as conductor of the Columbia Broadcasting Symphony Orchestra (1927-1943) and as conductor for the Voice of Firestone radio broadcast (1943-1958). He was also appointed conductor of the Baltimore Symphony Orchestra in the fall of 1939.
Among the materials are many orchestral arrangements produced by Mr. Barlow. In the inventory the use of asterisks denotes the following: If there are no asterisks, the arrangements are complete (orchestra parts and conductor score). One * asterisk denotes parts only, no conductor score. Two ** asterisks denotes a commercially printed score. Three *** asterisks denotes piano/vocal only (basis for a recording of lullabies). Barlow also composed many choral arrangements and orchestral works, some of which were commercially printed during the early 1920s (Series 3).
After Barlow left full-time radio conducting, he began to write short scripts around interesting musical personalities and events. These he hoped to record with his own voice and commercially distribute via Playback Productions of Mt. Kisco, New York. Prospective Scripts (box 7, folders 1-18), contains the variety of materials that he produced in drafts. Some were recorded as examples and brought/sent to radio stations. They All Made Music contains the vast majority (sequentially numbered to 146) of the short five-minute segments that Barlow was hoping to sell as a filler series. Music Notes appear to be similar in length to those for They All Made Music, but are more personal, i.e., Barlow's own experiences, or connections to persons he had known.
Barlow recorded one 50-minute program about Christmas (box 3). Otherwise there are no known extant records of any of the few that he may have taped. Apparently, many of the ideas for the short scripts came from articles in Keyboard Jr. and Young Keyboard Jr.
Scrapbooks of his career were maintained by his mother, Mrs. E. W. Barlow, of Portland, Oregon. An article about Mrs. Barlow is on page 52 of Scrapbook II (box 8).
In the summer of 1951, Columbia University's Oral History project interviewed Howard Barlow as part of their "Radio Pioneers" collection. The University provided Barlow with a bound copy of the transcription of the interviews, which can be found in Oversized Box 9.
The Research Materials and Sources (boxes 10-11) were compiled by James Pegolotti during his many years of research on the life of Howard Barlow. This resulted in the lengthy biographical article "Howard Barlow and The Rise and Fall of Classical Music on Commercial Radio" published in Connecticut Review, Volume XVII, No. 1, Spring, 1995. The research materials collected during his research supplement those already in the Barlow Collection initiated in 1999.
Related Material
Barlow's genealogy site.
Separated Material
Materials listed on the original inventory which are no longer in the collection:
Orchestral Arrangements by Howard Barlow
1. McDowell, Edward. To A Wild Rose (complete orchestra parts and conductor score)
2. Schubert, Franz. Moment Musical (complete orchestra parts and conductor score)
3. Schuman, Robert. Trumerei (complete orchestra parts and conductor score)
4. Smetena, Bedrich. Dance of the Comedians (complete orchestra parts and conductor score)
5. Taylor, Deems. Through the Looking Glass (parts only, no conductor score, commercially printed score)
Arrangement
The files are grouped into 13 series:
Series 1: Activities
Series 2: Columbia Broadcasting System
Series 3: Compositions by Howard Dunham Barlow
Series 4: HDB Guest Conducted Orchestra Concerts (reviews), 1940-1942
Series 5: Oral History
Series 6: Orchestral Arrangements by HDB (See Scope & Content Note for *guide)
Series 7: Photographs, 1938-ca 1960
Series 8: Prospective Scripts by HDB, ca 1960
Series 9: Scrapbooks
Series 10: Writings: Newspapers and Magazines, 1924-1969
Series 11: Phonograph RecordsSeries
Series 12: Miscellany
Series 13: Research Materials on the Life of Howard Dunham Barlow
Broadcasting -- United States; Conductors (Music) -- United States.; Fliers (printed matter); Conducting.; Composers -- United States; Clippings.; Correspondence.; Phonograph records.; Scores.; Programs.; Photographs.; Plain City (Ohio); New York (N.Y.); Bethel (Conn.); Audiotapes.; Bowes, Edward, Major, 1874-1946.; Braslau, Sophie, 1888-1935.; Bussler, Ludwig, 1838-1900.; Carnegie Hall (New York, N.Y.); Columbia Broadcasting Symphony; Columbia Broadcasting System, inc.; Columbia Masterworks Records; American National Orchestra; Barlow family; Barlow, Howard, 1892-1972.; Barlow, Jeannette.; Fletcher, Lucille; Firestone, Raymond Christy, 1908-1994.; Harrison, Lou, 1917-2003.; Gould, Morton, 1913-1996.; Hutcheson, Ernest, 1871-1951.; Herrmann, Bernard, 1911-1975.; Lynch, Christopher; James, Hugh, 1915-; Crooks, Richard; Connor, Nadine; Diebel, Wendel; Daniels, Oliver; Farrell, Eileen, 1920-2002.; Erskine, John; Firestone Orchestra; Ferris, Fred (Rev.); Sarnoff, David, 1891-1971.; Shine, William; Rodzinski, Artur, 1892-1958.; Rossomando, Frederic.; Stevens, Rise, 1913-; Swarthout, Gladys, 1900-1969.; Sigma Alpha Iota; Steber, Eleanor.; Miller, Mitch; Ovens, David D. (David Dunn).; March of time (Radio program).; Milhaud, Darius, 1892-1974.; Playback Productions; Plummer, Roger; Paley, William S. (William Samuel), 1901-; Pegolotti, James A.; Voorhees, Donald.; Voice of Firestone (Television program); Voice of Firestone (Radio program); Taylor, Davidson, 1907-; Work, Julian, 1910-1995.; Whiteman, Paul, 1890-1967.
- Series 1: Activities
  - Activities, 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Activities, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Activities, 1925 (Box OS 8)
    General note
    (Carnegie Hall Programs: The Garden of Mystery, March 20, (partial); Maria Theresa, April 6 (partial); Maria Theresa, February 13)
  - Activities, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Activities, 1931 (Box OS 8)
    (Carnegie Hall Program: The Philharmonic-Symphony Society, November 1)
  - Activities, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Activities, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Activities, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Activities, 1937 (Box OS 8)
    (Layout for The Etude and Cosmopolitan)
  - Activities, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Activities, 1938 (Box OS 8)
    (Magazine clippings)
  - Activities, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Activities, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Activities, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Activities, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Activities, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Activities, 1943 (Folder OS Folder 5.1)
    Columbia Masterworks Records ad - missing - BS 2017-08-22
  - Activities, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Activities, 1944 (Folder OS Folder 5.2)
    (Poster: Standard Oil Company, 75th Anniversary Radio Broadcast and Concert)
  - Activities, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Activities, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Activities, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Activities, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Activities, American-National Orchestra, 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Activities, American-National Orchestra, 1923-1924 (Box OS 8)
    Clippings from Musical America, Musical Monitor, and reprint from Baltimore Sun
  - Activities, March of Time, 1936-1938 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    (see also: Scrapbook II, p.50)
  - Activities, Playback Productions, 1961-1965 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Activities, Recordings Reviews, 1939-1944 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Activities, Voice of Firestone, 1943-1957 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Activities, Student Orchestras, 1958-1966 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Activities, Non-Musical Life, 1942-1966 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    (includes wife Jeannette)
  - Activities, Correspondence, 1925-1965 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    (to and from)
  - Awards, Sigma Alpha Iota, Aug 1941 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Awards, Ohio Career Medal, Oct 24, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Awards, Sylvania Television Awards, 1955 (Box OS 9)
  - Awards, Television Today Award of Achievement, January 1, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Series 2: Columbia Broadcasting System
  - Columbia Broadcasting System Program Logs Conducted by HDB, 1932-1937
    - CBS Symphony Orchestra, 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - CBS Symphony Orchestra, Soloist Gladys Rice, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - CBS Symphony Orchestra, Soloists, Grand Opera Miniatures, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - CBS Symphony Orchestra, Soloists, Mildred Rose and Charles Carlile, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - CBS Symphony Orchestra, Soloist Maude Rooney, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - CBS Symphony Orchestra, Soloist, Ernest Hutcheson, Piano, 1933-1934 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Columbia Symphonic Hour, 1933-1934 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - New World Symphony/Howard Barlow, 1933-1934 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - CBS Symphony Orchestra, Musical Album, 1933-1935 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - CBS Symphony Orchestra, Soloist Mary Eastman, 1933-1935 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - CBS Symphony Orchestra, Christmas and New Years Concerts, 1933-1939 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - CBS Symphony Orchestra, From Old Vienna, Soloists Rhoda Arnold and Mary Eastman, 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - CBS Symphony Orchestra, Melody Masterpieces, Soloists Mary Eastman and Evan Evans, 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - CBS Symphony Orchestra, On the Village Green, 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      (dances from around world)
    - CBS Symphony Orchestra, Columbia Concert Hall, 1935-1939 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - CBS Symphony Orchestra, Pop Concert, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - CBS Symphony Orchestra, Dinner Concert, 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - CBS Concert Orchestra, 1937-1942 (Box 2, Folder 18-19)
    - CBS Symphony Orchestra, Soloist Clyde Barrie, 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - CBS Symphony Orchestra, Soloist Margaret Daum, 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - CBS Symphony Orchestra, Soloist Hollace Shaw, 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - CBS Symphony Orchestra, Everybody's Music, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - CBS Symphony Orchestra, Music for Fun, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - CBS Symphony Orchestra, Soloist Genevieve Rowe, 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - CBS Symphony Orchestra, Sunday Summer Replacement of New York Philharmonic Orchestra, 1940-1942 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - CBS Symphony Orchestra, The Lyric Stage, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - CBS Symphony Orchestra, Columbia's American Festival, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - CBS Symphony Orchestra, Songs of the Centuries, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - CBS Symphony Orchestra, Stars in the Orchestra, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - CBS Symphony Orchestra, Soloist Eileen Farrell, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - CBS Symphony Orchestra, British-American Festival, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - CBS Symphony Orchestra, Special Orchestral Programs, 1935-1937 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      (Minneapolis Symphony 3/8/35; salute to Pan-American Conference, 12/14/36; Norwegian Independence Day 5/17/37)
    - Lanny Ross State Fair Concert Logs, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Series 3: Compositions by Howard Dunham Barlow
  - Art Songs (choral arrangements by HDB), Published by J. Fischer & Brother
    - The Cruise, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      (men 4-part)
    - Hush of the World, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      (2 copies) (women 3-part)
    - Love Is So New, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      (women 3-part)
    - Love is So New (with hush of the world, your eyes), 1923 (Box 4, Folder 3.1)
      General
      2 copies of each, inscribed.
    - Where Runs the River, SABT, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Your Eyes, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Art Songs (choral arrangements by HDB), Publisher: G. Ricordi & Co.
    - At the Gates of Sevil; Composer: Felix Fourdrain, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Because; Composer: A. Gretchainow, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Body and Soul; Composer: A. Walter Kramer, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - The Dark Firelit; Composer: Thomas Winston, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      (SABT)
    - The Dark Firelit; Composer: Thomas Winston, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - The Flowers of the Forest; Composer: anonymous, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      (SATB)
    - God in Nature; Composer: L. Van Beethoven, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - The Great Awakenings; Composer: A. Walter Kramer, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - The Islands of the Sky; Composer Maximilian Pilzer, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      (women 3-part
    - The Love Immortal; Composer N. Rimsky-Korsakow, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Lullaby; Composer: M. H. LeBaron, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Mary and I; Composer Dwight Fiske, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Mulberry Tree; Composer: John B. Wells, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - My Heart's a Yellow Butterfly; Composer: C. H. Bochau, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - My Mother; Composer: G. S. White, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - My Native Land! Composer: A. Gretchaninow, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - The Stork and the Skylark; Composer: Felix Fourdrain, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - The Wounded Birch; Composer: A. Gretchaninow, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - The Yellow Dove; Composer: Felix Fourdrain, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Zuleika (Song of Zuleika); Composer: Rimsky-Korsakov, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Orchestral Works, 1914-1924
    - The Prologue: Everywoman's Road: A Morality of Woman by Josephine Hammond, Music by HDB., 1914 (Box OS 8)
      Manuscript: voice/piano
    - Song of Idas, undated (Box OS 2)
      (aka Marpessa) Tone Poem for Orchestra and Tenor Voice. 1917 Music by HDB; from the poem Marpessa by Stephen Phillips. Manuscript (full score, all parts)
    - Within a Temple., 1922 (Box OS 8)
      (tone poem) 1922 Music by HDB. Manuscript (full score)
  - Songs (manuscript and commercially printed), 1919-1924
    - My Heart Leaps Up, 1919 (Box OS 8)
      Music by HDB; words by William Wordsworth Manuscript (full score) (song)
    - Margaret, 1920 (Box OS 8)
      Music by HDB; words by James Rogers (song for high voice)
    - Lament, The Garden, 1924 (Box OS 8)
      Composers' Music Corporation Music by HDB; poem from the Chinese (for voice and piano)
    - Mother, I Cannot Mind My Wheel; Margaret, 1922 (Box OS 8)
  - Miscellany
    - A Christmas Narrative with Howard Barlow, 1964 (Box 3)
      1964 Script and reel-to-reel recording: Part One, Reel #1, 26:40; Part Two, Reel #2, 23:20, and one cassette tape
    - Continuity Music (possibly for March of Time radio program): 12 partial compositions, undated (Box OS 10)
    - Continuity Music (possibly for March of Time radio program): Religious/Christmas Music, undated (Box OS 10)
      Laudi Alla Virgine Maria (G.Verdi)
      Adoration of the Shepherds
      Three Kings
      Flight into Egypt
      Hebrew Chant
  - Variety of manuscript songs and brief orchestral pieces, 1911-1914
    - Mary!, 1911 (Box OS 10)
      (words by Robert Burns)
    - Aspatia's Song, undated (Box OS 10)
      (John Fletcher)
    - Visions, undated (Box OS 10)
      (words by Paul Hyde Bonner)
    - Ballet, undated (Box OS 10)
    - A Moving Picture Show, Sep 8, 1914 (Box OS 10)
    - Pastoral, Nov 13, 1914 (Box OS 10)
    - A Lad Sings, undated (Box OS 10)
    - Springtime Waltz Song, undated (Box OS 10)
      Arranged by HDB.
- Series 4: HDB Guest Conducted Orchestra Concerts (reviews), 1940-1942
  - Philadelphia Orchestra, Robin Hood Dell, Fairmount Park, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Musical America, Sep 1933 (Box OS 10)
  - New York Philharmonic, Lewisohn Stadium, 1934-1942 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    (Fokine Russian Ballet, Muriel Dickson, Ania Dorfman, Josef Lhevinne)
  - National Symphony (D.C.), 1936 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Duluth Symphony, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Baltimore Symphony Orchestra, 1939-1942 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Hollywood Bowl, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    (Yehudi Menuhin)
  - Detroit Symphony, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Montreal Orchestre, Les Concerts Symphonique, 1941-1944 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - New York Philharmonic, Carnegie Hall, 1942-1943 (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
    (Artur Rubinstein, Robert Casadesus)
  - New York Philharmonic, Carnegie Hall Programs, 1942-1943 (Box 5, Folder 11-12)
  - Rochester, NY, Starlight Symphony, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Chicago Symphony, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 14-15)
    (Marjorie Lawrence, Carrol Glenn, Arnaldo Estrella)
  - Seattle and Vancouver Symphony Orchestras, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Fairfield (CT) "Pops", 1949 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    ((Eleanor Steber)
  - Indianapolis Symphony Orchestra, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Buffalo Philharmonic, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    (Gladys Swarthout)
  - Milwaukee "Pops", 1954-1962 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    (Gordon MacRae, Brian Sullivan, Robert Rounseville)
  - Toronto Symphony, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    (Irene Jordan)
  - Miami "Pops", 1958-1963 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - New Orleans Summer Pops, 1960-1962 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - New Orleans Summer Pops/Honorary Citizen of New Orleans, Aug 20, 1960 (Box OS 10)
- Series 5: Oral History
  - Reminiscences of Howard Barlow, 1951 (Box OS 9)
    (transcribed/l bound copy)
- Series 6: Orchestral Arrangements by HDB (See Scope & Content Note for *guide)
  - Beethoven, Ludwig: Symphony no. 7, undated (Box OS 1)
    Manuscript with notes
  - Borodin, Alexander: Prince Igor, Oriental Dances*,**, undated (Box OS 1)
  - Brahms, Johannes Synthesis SG 1, undated (Box OS 1)
  - Brahms, Johannes: Syntheses SG 2, undated (Box OS 1)
  - Chopin, Frédéric, undated (Box OS 1)
  - Cui, Cesa: Orientale*, undated (Box OS 1)
  - Donizetti, Gaetano: Lucia di Lamermoore, Sextette, undated (Box OS 1)
  - Franck, Cesar: Symphony in D Minor: Synthesis, undated (Box OS 1)
  - Friml, Rudolph: Donkey Serenade, undated (Box OS 1)
  - Gluck, Christoph: Iphegenie in Aulis, Overture, undated (Box OS 2)
  - Godard, Benjamin: Jocelyn*, undated (Box OS 2)
  - Mendelssohn, Felix: Midsummer Night's Dream "Wedding March" *,**, undated (Box OS 2)
  - Mozart, Wolfgang: Marriage of Figaro, "Voi che sapete" *,**, undated (Box OS 2)
  - Mozart, Wolfgang: Marriage of Figaro, Overture, undated (Box OS 2)
  - Lehmann, Liza: In a Persian Garden, undated (Box OS 3)
  - Leoncavello, Ruggiero: Pagliacci, Intermezzo, undated (Box OS 3)
  - McDowell, Edward: AD 1620*, undated (Box OS 3)
  - Mussorgsky, Modeste: Boris Goudonov, Kazan, undated (Box OS 3)
  - Mascagni, Pietro: Cavelleria Rusticana "Intermezzo", undated (Box OS 4)
  - Nevin, Ethelbert: Canzone Amorosa (Boat Song), undated (Box OS 4)
  - Offenbach, Jacques: Orpheus in the Underworld, Overture*,**, undated (Box OS 4)
  - Rimsky-Korsakov, N.: Serbian Fantasy*, undated (Box OS 4)
  - Schubert, Franz: Serenade, undated (Box OS 5)
  - Tchaikovsky, Peter: Overture 1812, Synthesis with chorus, undated (Box OS 5)
  - Tchaikovsky, Peter: Overture 1812 (printed), undated (Box OS 5)
  - Tchaikovsky, Peter: Overture 1812, undated (Box OS 5)
  - Tchaikovsky, Peter: Overture 1812, 1966 (Box OS 5)
  - Tchaikovsky, Peter: Capriccio Italien, Synthesis, undated (Box OS 6)
  - Tchaikovsky, Peter: Nutcracker Suite, Dances*, undated (Box OS 6)
  - Traditional: Londonderry Air, undated (Box OS 7)
  - Traditional: Deep River, undated (Box OS 7)
  - Traditional: Lullabies, Variety***, undated (Box OS 7)
  - Verdi, Giuseppe: Rigoletto, Quartette, undated (Box OS 7)
  - Verdi, Giuseppe: Il Trovatore: Finale Act III, "To Arms", undated (Box OS 7)
  - Wagner, Richard: Tannhauser: Evening Star, undated (Box OS 7)
- Series 7: Photographs, 1938-ca 1960
  - HDB, Major Edward Bowes and Wendel Diebel, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - HDB and Paul Whiteman, ca.1940 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - HDB, Darius Milhaud, members of CBS Symphony, and Darius Milhaud conducting CBS Symphony, ca.1940 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    (four photos)
  - HDB and "Buck" the Saint Bernard, ca.1941 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    (two photos)
  - HDB receiving Distinguished Service Award of Sigma Alpha Iota, presented by Gertrude Evans, National President and HDB's mother, Aug 19, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    (three photos)
  - HDB and Gladys Swarthout, ca.1943 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - HDB and Richard Crooks, ca.1943 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - HDB and Hugh James, ca.1945 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    (announcer) unknown man and woman
  - HDB and Eleanor Steber, candid shot, rehearsal for Voice of Firestone, May 10, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - HDB in rehearsal for early telecast of Voice of Firestone, ca.1948 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - HDB and Nadine Connor in rehearsal for telecast, ca.1950 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - HDB, Nadine Connor, Hugh James and two unidentified men, ca.1950 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - HDB in rehearsal with two unidentified men [directors?], ca.1950 (Box 6, Folder 13)